A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- SIX SONATES en Trio Pour deux Violons e Violoncello, COMPOSÉE Par Messieurs BEZZOSSI Ordinaires de la Musique du Roy de Sardaigne. Fait gravé par Mr. CANAVASSE. Prix 7tt. en blanc Se Vend à Paris Chés Mr. CANAVASSE Cadet au Petit Luxembourg Chés S.A.S. Madame la Princesse de Carignan. Mr. Castagne
  Trio sonatas. Selections; Besozzi, Antonio, 1714-1781; Besozzi, Paolo Girolamo, 1704-1778; Besozzi, Alessandro, 1702-1793; Canavasse, Mr.; Castagneri, Andrea; Guersan, Louis, ca. 1700-1770; Canavasse, Mr.; Estien, Mlle.; Paris (France); Minuet; A; B♭; C; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Minuetto
  Letter of royal privilege. 1739 is the only date given for Canavasse by Hopkinson, p. 21.
  RISM identifies this set as the work of Alessandro, Girolamo (1704-1778), and Antonio (1714-1781) Besozzi.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- VI SONATAS in Three Parts FOR A GERMAN FLUTE, A VIOLIN with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD or VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. Alexandro Bezozzi Musician in Ordinary to the King of Sardinia London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of Whom may be had [list of works beginning with: "I. Six Sonatas for two German Flutes and a Bass by Sigr. Pietro Locatelli, Opera Terza." and ending with: "VI. Lampugnani, St. Martini of Milan, and Brioschi's Sonatas for two Violins and a Bass, Three Sets."], 1747; B2458; Three parts, folio, 243x174 (253x185): TRAVERSO E VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Same as TRAVERSO E VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10].
  SONATA III a
  SONATA VI G
  Trio sonatas. Selections; Besozzi, Alessandro, 1702-1793; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; C; D; G; A; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Andantino; Largo; Minuetto; Presto
  Smith-Humphries, no. 156. Announced in
  General Advertiser
  , September 30, 1747.
  RISM: questions the authenticity of at least some works in this set ("Von verschiedenen Komponisten?"), but Guido Salvetti ("Besozzi," The New Grove, v. 2, p. 660) does not.
  - TRAVERSO E VIOLINO PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- VIII SONATAS FOR TWO GERMAN FLUTES OR TWO VIOLINS with a BASS for the VIOLONCELLO or HARPSICORD Compos'd by Sigr. ALEXANDRO BEZOZZI Musician in Ordinary to the King of Sardinia. Opera Terza. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had Just Publish'd For 2 German Flutes & a Bass [list of works beginning with: "Defesch's 12 Sonatas" and ending with: "Hasse, Galuppi, & Vinci's Aires"], 1750; B2452 ("harpsichord"); Three parts, folio, 248x179 (255x185): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. SECONDO: Same as PRIMO. BASSO: Same as PRIMO.
  Minuet Allegro 3/4
  SONATA III d
  Presto 2/4
  SONATA IV a
  SONATA V G
  [no indication] 3/4
  SONATA VII D
  SONATA VIII F
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Besozzi, Alessandro, 1702-1793; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; C; D; F; G; A; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegretto; Allegro; Andante; Minuet allegro; Presto; [no indication]
  Smith-Humphries, no. 157. Announced in
  , May 17-19, 1750.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SONATE à Tre Due Violini e Violoncello col Basso Per l'Organo DA GIO. BIANCHI. Violinista Milanese OPERA PRIMA. A Amsterdam Chez ESTIENNE ROGER Marchand libraire., 1702; B2587; Three parts, folio, 223x123 (300x183): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-13. Blank, [14]. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-12. Violoncello: Same as Violino Secondo. Organo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-15. Blank, [16]. Three parts, folio, 223x123 (300x183): "1708" added in MS on title-page of Violino Primo between "OPERA PRIMA" and "A Amsterdam".
  Sonata I G
  Adagio ma Andante C [in Violoncello: "Largo ma Andante"]
  Adagio 3/2 - Presto 3/4
  Presto 3/4
  Sonata II a
  Sonata V D
  Sonata VI e
  Sonata VII F
  Largo ma Andante C
  Presto 6/8
  Sonata VIII g
  Presto e Staccato C
  Sonata X b
  Sonata XI c
  Sonata XII A
  Adagio C - Presto C
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Bianchi, Giovanni, b. ca. 1660; Roger, Estienne, 1665-1722; Amsterdam (Netherlands); A; B♭; C; D; F; G; B; E; 12/8; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; Adagio; Adagio ma andante; Allegro; Largo; Largo ma andante; Presto; Presto e staccato; Spiritoso
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Violoncello
  - Organo
- Sonate a due Violino, e Basso Per Suonarsi con Flauto, o'vero Violino del Signor Martino Bitti Sonator di Violino Del Serenissmo Gran Principe di Toscana Solos with his Graces, Pepusch's 24 Solos, Bomporti's Solos, Albinonis Solos. LONDON, Printed for J. Walsh Servt. to her Majesty at ye Harp & Hoboy in Katherine Street in ye Strand, & J. Hare at ye Viol & Flute in Cornhill near ye Royal Exchange., 1711; B2758; Score, oblong folio, 148x190 (153x197): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-32.
  Preludio Vivace C
  Corrente Vivace 3/4
  Gavotta Presto C|
  Minuette Allegro 3/4
  SONATA IV g
  Preludio Largo 3/2
  Allemanda Vivace C
  SONATA V c
  Sarabanda Largo 3/2
  Preludio Andante C
  SONATA VII d
  Trio sonatas; Bitti, Martino; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Viol and Flute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Allemande; Corrente; Gavotte; Jig; Minuet; Prelude; Sarabande; B♭; C; F; G; A; D; 12/8; 3/2; 3/4; C|; Allemanda allegro; Allemanda vivace; Corrente allegro; Corrente vivace; Gavotta presto; Giga allegro; Minuette allegro; Preludio andante; Preludio largo; Preludio vivace; Sarabanda largo
  Smith no. 396. Announced in
  Post Man
  , December 11-13, 1711.
  - SCORE
- Six DUETS For a Violin and TENOR. BY B. Blake. Price 7/6. London, Printed for Willm. Napier No. 474, Strand., 1780?; B2823; Two parts, quarto, 256x184 (276x201): VIOLINO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLA: Same as VIOLINO. Plate no. 76 throughout. Bound with nos. 40, 107, 181, and 210.
  DUETTO I C
  Allo. moderato C|
  DUETTO II F
  Allo. moderato 2/4
  DUETTO III D
  DUETTO IV G
  DUETTO V A
  DUETTO VI E♭
  Duets, violin, viola, op. 1; Blake, Benjamin, 1751-1827; Napier, William, 1740?-1812; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; C; D; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; C|; Allegro moderato; Rondo allegretto; Tempo di minuetto
  CPM
  BUCEM dates this as 1781.
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLA
- Six QUARTETTOS for two VIOLINS, TENOR and VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO, Compos'd by Sigr. Luigi Boccherini Opera VI. Pr. 10/6 LONDON Printed & sold by R: Bremner, opposite Somerset House Strand, of whom may be had [list of works beginning with: "Abel's Quartettos Op. 2." and ending with: "Toeoshis...Do."], 1790?; B3117; Four parts, quarto, 243x179 (248 x 184): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, 1-16. Two blanks. VIOLION SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLA: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO. VIOLONCELLO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  QUARTETTO I c
  [G. 166]
  QUARTETTO II D
  [G.165]
  Rondeau Allegro 3/4
  [G.167]
  Tempo di Menuetto 3/4
  QUARTETTO IV g
  [G. 168]
  [G. 169]
  Andantino Con Poco Moto 2/4
  [G.170]
  Allegro Brilliante C
  Amoroso 6/8
  Quartets, strings, G. 165-170; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; D; E♭; F; C; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro brillante; Amoroso; Andantino con poco moto; Grave; Largo; Moderato; Rondeau allegro; Tempo di menuetto
  Gerard (p. 184) dates this as ca. 1775.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLION SECONDO
  - VIOLA
  - VIOLONCELLO
- SEI TRIETTI Per Due Violini, et Basso. Composte del Signore LUIGI, BOCCHERINI. OPÉRA II. Prix 9 fr. A PARIS Chez IMBAULT Md de Musique de Leurs Majestés JJ. et RR. et Musicien honoraire de leur Chapelle Au Mont d'Or, Rue St. Honoré No. 125 entre l'Hôtel d'Aligre et la Rue des Poulies Et Péristile du Théâtre de l'Opéra Comique Rue Favart No. 461., ca. 1810; B3058; Three parts, quarto, 257x192 (264x198): VIOLINO Io.: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-15. Blank, [16]. VIOLINO 2o.: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO 2o. Bound with nos. 33, 34, and 35.
  Io. TRIO F
  Allo. non tanto C
  IIo. TRIO B♭
  Largo Assai 3/4
  Presto Assai 2/4
  IIIo. TRIO A
  IVo. TRIO D
  Allegro Con spirito C
  Fuga Allegro C|
  Vo. TRIO G
  Larghetto 3/8
  Allegro Con brio C
  VIo. TRIO C
  Allegro Brioso 2/4
  Trios, strings, G. 77-82; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Imbault, Jean Jérôme; Paris (France); Fugue; Minuet; A; B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro brioso; Allegro con brio; Allegro con spirito; Allegro non tanto; Fuga allegro; Larghetto; Largo; Largo assai; Presto; Presto assai; Tempo di minuetto
  Gerard, p. 78.
  - VIOLINO Io.
  - VIOLINO 2o.
  - BASSO
- SIX TRIOS pour Violon, Alto et Basse, Composés PAR L. BOCCHERINI. Huitième Livre. Œuv. 38. Prix: 10f. A PARIS, Chez JANET et COTELLE, Editeurs Marchands de Musique du ROI, au Mont d'Or, Rue St. Honoré, No. 125, entre celle des Poulies et l'Hôtel d'Aligre., 1824; B3097; Three parts, quarto, 246x193 (264x198): VIOLINO: Title, [147]. Music, pp. 148-161. Blank, [162]. VIOLA: Title, [139]. Music, pp. 140-151. Blank, [152]. VIOLONCELLO: Title, [115]. Music, pp. 116-127. Blank, [128]. Plate no. I4I9 throughout. Bound with nos. 32, 34, and 35.
  TRIO I A
  Allegro moderato 2/4
  Minuetto Amoroso 3/4
  TRIO 2 G
  Andantino 6/8
  TRIO 3 B♭
  Andante Allegretto 2/4
  TRIO 4 E♭
  TRIO 5 D
  Andante moderato assai C
  TRIO 6 F
  Allegretto moderato assai C
  Allegro Non tanto 2/4
  Trios, strings, G. 107-112; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Janet et Cotelle; Paris (France); Minuet; A; B♭; D; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C; Adagio; Allegretto moderato assai; Allegro non tanto; Allegro moderato; Andante allegretto; Andante moderato assai; Andantino; Minuetto amoroso; Tempo di minuetto
  Gerard, p. 123
  Issued as the eighth book of the composer's "Collection des trios pour deux violons et basse... livre 1[-9]".
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLA
  - VIOLONCELLO
- Six TRIO POUR deux Violons & Basse PAR Luigi Boccherini ŒUVRE IIIE. PRIX 7 tt. 10s. A PARIS [imprint obscured by label: "A Paris chez Augte. Le Duc Editeur et Marchand de Musique Rue de la Loi No. 267 prés celle Faydeau. Jnstruments de Musique a Vendre et a Louer."], Between 1804 and 1825; Deest; Three parts, quarto, 253x188 (280x207): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-16. Violino Secondo ou Violoncello: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18]. Basso: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Unfigured. The label on the title-page obscures an earlier Le Duc imprint, but the address is not legible. Plate no. 133 throughout. Bound with nos. 32, 33, and 35.
  TRIO Io. C
  TRIO IIo. A
  Allegro Moderato 2/4
  TRIO IIIo. A
  Allo Moderato 2/4
  Largo 3/8
  TRIO IVo. D
  Allegro Molto 3/4
  TRIO Vo. D
  Allegro non tanto C
  Allegro assai C|
  TRIO VIo. E♭
  Minuto. 3/4
  Trios, violins, violoncello, G. 119-124; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Leduc, Auguste (Antoine-Pierre-Auguste), 1779-1823; Leduc, Auguste (Antoine-Pierre-Auguste), 1779-1823; Paris (France); Minuet; A; C; D; E♭; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro molto; Allegro assai; Allegro non tanto; Largo; Minuetto; Tempo di minuetto
  Le Duc moved to this address in 1804 and died between 1822 and 1825 (Hopkinson, p. 76). Gerard does not cite this issue.
  Gerard considers these works to be of doubtful authenticity. Le Duc published these same works ca. 1795, but with a different title-page and with the plate no. 212.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo ou Violoncello
  - Basso
- Six TRIO pour deux Violons et Violoncelle COMPOSéS Par L. BOCCHERINI Œuvre 7e. Prix 9tt. A PARIS Chez Naderman, Rue de la Loi, à la Clef d'Or, Passage de l'ancien Caffé de foy. [in lower left corner: "n.f."], ca. 1795?; B3073 (plate no. 1003); Three parts, quarto, 260x189 (266x198): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino Secondo: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Same as Violino Secondo. Unfigured. Bound with nos. 32, 33, and 34.
  TRIO I c
  All. staccato C
  And. Cantabile 2/4
  All. assai C
  TRIO III E♭
  TRIO V B♭
  TRIO VI F
  And. assai 2/4
  Trios, violins, violoncello, G. 125-130; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Naderman, Jean-Henri, 1735-1799; Paris (France); Minuet; A; B♭; D; E♭; F; C; 2/4; 3/4; Allegro assai; Allegro staccato; Allegro; Andante cantabile; Andante assai; Andante; Largo; Minuetto
  Gerard, p.142.
  The authenticity of these works has been questioned, but Gerard (pp. 140-141) considers them to be authentic.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- A Third Set of SIX TRIOS For two VIOLINS and a VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO with a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICHORD Composed by L. BOCCHERINI. Opera IX. Pr. 7s. 6d. LONDON. Printed and Sold by R: BREMNER opposite Somerset House in the STRAND., 1772 or ca. 1775; B3076; Three parts, quarto, 232x144 (261x186): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-14. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  [G. 91]
  Andantino Gratioso 2/4
  Allegro maestoso C
  [G. 89]
  Andantino Amoroso 2/4
  Allegro molto 2/4
  Tempo di Minuet 3/4
  [G. 90]
  Allo. Maestoso C
  Andante Gratioso 3/4
  Allegro molto C|
  [G. 92]
  Lento con Expresione 2/4
  SONATA V g
  [G. 93]
  Rondeau Allegro 2/4
  [G. 94]
  Allo. assai C|
  Trio sonatas, G. 89-94; Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro maestoso; Allegro molto; Allegro assai; Andante grazioso; Andantino amoroso; Andantino grazioso; Larghetto; Lento con expresione; Minuetto amoroso; Presto; Rondeau allegro; Tempo di minuet; Tempo di minuetto
  Gerard, p. 101 dates this as ca. 1775.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- XII SONATAS For the Chamber For two Violins and a Bass doubled Dedicated To her Grace the Dutchess Dowager of MARLBOROUGH BY John Bononcini. Printed at London Anno 1732 Price One Guinea., 1732. Title-page; B3618; Three parts, folio, 213x177 (256x182): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, royal privilege, in letterpress, dated "5 November 1731" and signed "Harrington". Letter of dedication, verso blank, [i-ii]. Music, pp. 1-23. Blank, [24]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-20. BASSO (2 copies): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-19. Blank, [20].
  SONATA I F
  Moderato 3/4
  Lento 3/4
  Allegro 2
  Menuet non Presto 3/8
  Vivace 2
  Menuet non Presto 3/4
  Andante Moderato C
  Presto 2
  Affettuoso 3/4
  Menuet Presto 3/4
  Tempo Moderato C
  Menuet Vivace 3/4
  Moderato e Affettuoso C
  Con Spirito 3/4
  Adagio e Piano C
  SONATA VII c
  Vivace 12/8
  Menuet Moderato 3/8
  SONATA VIII G
  Adagio C - Tempo giusto C
  Menuet Allegro 3/8
  SONATA IX b
  Adagio 3/4 - Vivace C
  Menuet Andante Largo 3/8
  SONATA X E
  Largo Andante C
  Lento e dolce 3/4
  Menuet Spiritoso 3/4
  SONATA XI d
  Tempo giusto C
  Spiritoso 3/4
  SONATA XII f
  Largo C - Non Presto, e Staccato C
  Menuet Andante 3/8
  Trio sonatas; Bononcini, Giovanni, 1670-1747; London (England); Minuet; A; B♭; C; D; E; F; G; B; 12/8; 2; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Adagio e piano; Affettuoso; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Andante moderato; Con spirito; Largo; Largo andante; Lento; Lento e dolce; Menuet allegro; Menuet andante; Menuet andante largo; Menuet moderato; Menuet presto; Menuet spiritoso; Menuet vivace; Menuet non presto; Moderato; Moderato e affettuoso; Non presto e staccato; Presto; Spiritoso; Tempo moderato; Tempo giusto; Vivace
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO (2 copies)
- Bomporti's SONATA'S or CHAMBER AIRES in three Parts for two VIOLINS and a THROUGH BASS Compos'd by Francisco Antonio Bomporti Opera 2d London Printed for I. Walsh Servt. to her Matie. at ye Harp & Hoboy in Katherine Street near Somerset House in ye Strand. I. Hare Instrument maker at ye Golden Viol & Flute in Cornhill near ye Royal Exchange - and P. Randall at ye Violin and Lute by Pauls grave head Court without Temple Barr in the Strand., ca. 1708; B3646.; Three parts, folio, 256x180 (263x185); all parts have music printed on recto only; all versos are blank and unnumbered: VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-14. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-11. BASSO CONTINUO (2 copies): Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  Allemanda Alleg e Vivace C
  Staccato e Adagissimo C
  Preludio Largo 3/4
  Corrente Conspirito 3/4
  SONATA III F
  Preludio Allemanda C
  Corrente Presto 3/4
  Giga Presto 12/8
  SONATA V E
  Preludio Adagio C
  Sarabanda Largo 3/4
  Sarabanda 3/4
  SONATA VII b
  Allemanda C
  Giga Alleg e Presto 12/8
  SONATA VIII C
  SONATA IX B♭
  Preludio C
  Sarabanda Allegro 6/4
  SONATA X G
  Ciaccona 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 2; Bonporti, Francesco Antonio, 1672-1749; Golden Viol and Flute; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Randall, Peter, fl. ca. 1706-1710; Violin and Lute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Allemande; Chaconne; Corrente; Gavotte; Jig; Prelude; Sarabande; A; B♭; C; D; E; F; G; B; 12/8; 3/4; 6/4; Adagio; Allemanda; Allemanda allegro e vivace; Allemanda allegro; Ciaccona; Corrente con spirito; Corrente presto; Gavotta allegro; Gavotta presto; Giga allegro e presto; Giga allegro; Giga presto; Grave; Preludio; Preludio adagio; Preludio allemanda; Preludio largo; Preludio vivace; Sarabanda; Sarabanda allegro; Sarabanda largo; Staccato e adagissimo
  Smith no. 266.
  ...The Monthly Masks of Vocal Musick... for the Year 1708
  (Smith no. 282a).
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO CONTINUO (2 copies)
- Bomporti's SONATA'S or CHAMBER AIRES in three Parts for two VIOLINS and a THROUGH BASS Compos'd by Francisco Antonio Bomporti Opera Quarto London Printed for I. Walsh Servt. to her Matie. at ye Harp & Hoboy in Katherine Street near Somerset House in ye Strand. I. Hare Instrument maker at ye Golden Viol & Flute in Cornhill near ye Royal Exchange - and P. Randall at ye Violin and Lute by Pauls grave head Court without Temple Barr in the Strand., ca. 1708; B3652; Three parts, folio, 256x181 (264x185): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-12. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-10. BASSO CONTINUO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  SONATA I g
  SONATA II b
  Preludio Andante 3/4
  Giga 12/8
  Adagio assai e Staccato C
  Corrente 3/4
  Sarabanda Adagio 3/4
  SONATA VIII e
  SONATA IX F
  SONATA X C
  Preludio Allegro C
  Allemand Allegro C
  Corente 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 4; Bonporti, Francesco Antonio, 1672-1749; Golden Viol and Flute; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Randall, Peter, fl. ca. 1706-1710; Violin and Lute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Allemande; Corrente; Gavotte; Jig; Prelude; Sarabande; A; B♭; C; D; E; F; B; G; 12/8; 3/4; C|; Adagio; Adagio assai e staccato; Allemande allegro; Allemanda allegro; Allemanda presto; Andante; Corrente; Corrente allegro; Corrente presto; Gavotta presto; Giga; Grave; Preludio adagio; Preludio allegro; Preludio andante; Preludio largo; Sarabanda; Sarabanda adagio; Sarabanda largo
  Smith no. 267.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO CONTINUO
- SIX DUETTS For a VIOLIN AND VIOLONCELLO OR VIOLIN and TENOR Composed & Humbly Dedicated to Ralph Sheldon Esqr. BY Lewis Borghi; Opa. V. Pr. 10s. 6d. For the Accomodation of the Public the Author has adapted the part of the Violoncello for the Tenor & printed it separately Printed for the Author And Sold at his House No. 5 John Street, Great Portland Street, where may be had all his Works And at Mr. Forsters Music Shop No. 348 near Exeter Change in the Strand., 1786; B3726; Three parts, quarto, 247x194 (275x201): VIOLINO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. VIOLONCELLO: Same as VIOLINO. Unfigured. VIOLA: Title-page reads: "Alto Viola". Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. Title-page of VIOLINO signed at bottom center: "L. Borghi 4". Bound with nos. 30, 107, 181, and 210.
  Rondeau Allegretto 6/8
  DUETTO II B♭
  Allo. con Spirito C|
  Rondeau Allegretto 2/4
  Maestoso C|
  Pastorale Allegretto 6/8
  Grazioso 3/4
  Rondeau Presto 3/8
  Duets, violin, violoncello, op. 5; Borghi, Luigi, b. ca. 1745; Mr. Forsters Music Shop; London (England); Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; E♭; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro con spirito; Grazioso; Largo; Maestoso; Pastorale allegretto; Rondeau allegretto; Rondeau presto
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLONCELLO
  - VIOLA
- EIGHT SYMPHONYS in Eight Parts. Six for Violins, Hoboys, or German Flutes. and Two for Violins, French Horns and Trumpets. with a Bass for the VIOLONCELLO and HARPSICORD. COMPOS'D BY Dr. Wm. BOYCE. OPERA SECONDA. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had by the same author. [list of works beginning with: "Twelve Sonatas for two Violins and a Bass." and ending with: "The Shepherd's Lottery and Chaplet in Score."] Just Publish'd for Concerts for Violins &c. [list of works beginning with: "Handel's 400 Selected Songs for the Harpsicord and Voice in 5 vols. and for Concerts for Violins &c. in 5 Parts."], 1759 or 1760; B4172; Nine parts, folio, 252x183 (266x190): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-19. Blank, [20]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-15. Blank, [16]. VIOLA: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music. pp. 2-11. Blank, [12]. BASSO (2 copies): Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-16. HAUTBOY PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-7. Blank, [8]. Music, pp. 9-13. Blank, [14]. HAUTBOY SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-11. Blank, [12]. CORNO: see TYMPANY. TROMBA PRIMO: Blank, [i]. Music, p. [1]. Bound with TYMPANY. TROMBA SECONDO: Music, p. [1]. Verso blank. TYMPANY: Music, p. [1]. Verso blank. Bottom half of page of music headed "CORNO", with braced doubled staves for "Corno 1o." and Corno 2o.". Bound with TROMBA PRIMO.
  SYMPHONY I B♭
  Moderato e Dolce 3/8
  SYMPHONY II A
  Vivace 2/4
  Presto Allegro 3/8
  SYMPHONY III C
  Vivace C|
  SYMPHONY IV F
  Vivace ma non troppo 9/8
  Gavot Allegro C|
  SYMPHONY V D
  Tempo di Gavotta C
  SYMPHONY VI F
  SYMPHONY VII B♭
  Spirituoso 9/8
  Jigg Allegro assai 6/8
  SYMPHONY VIII d
  Pomposo 3/2
  Symphonies, op. 2; Boyce, William, 1711-1779; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Gavotte; Jig; Minuet; A; B♭; C; D; F; 2/4; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; 9/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro ma non troppo; Andante; Gavot allegro; Jig allegro assai; Larghetto; Largo; Largo andante; Moderato; Moderato e dolce; Pomposo; Presto allegro; Spiritoso; Tempo di gavotta; Tempo di minuetto; Vivace; Vivace ma non troppo
  Smith-Humphries, no. 252.
  , January 5, 1760.
  Originally composed as overtures to eight of the composer's vocal works. See Robert J. Bruce's works-list in The New Grove, v. 3, pp. 142-143.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - VIOLA
  - BASSO (2 copies)
  - HAUTBOY PRIMO
  - HAUTBOY SECONDO
  - CORNO
  - TROMBA PRIMO
  - TROMBA SECONDO
  - TYMPANY